A Guide to the Cocke and related families Papers
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #2433-ag
Cocke and related families Papers ca. 1851, 1926-1980
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
2433-ag
ca. 330 items
Mrs. Philip St. George Cocke, IV
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
This collection was given to the University of Virginia Library on August 28, 1996, by Mrs. Philip St. George Cocke, IV, Rappahannock Academy, Virginia.
Scope and Content
This collection consists of correspondence of Philip St. George Cocke IV (1908-?), genealogical notes and charts, photostatic copies of wills and deeds from Virginia and England, coat of arms, catalogues, research notes, photographs, newsclippings, topical files, and related material, ca. 330 items (2 Hollinger boxes and 2 oversize folders, ca. 1 linear foot), ca. [1851], 1926-1980, on the Cocke and allied families, compiled by Philip St. George Cocke, IV.
Correspondents with individual folders include: William Ronald Cocke, Alice L. de Coligny, Elie Maury Fitzgerald, R.P. Graham-Vivian, T.P. Hughes, Forney & Joseph F. Johnston, Roberta McDonald Russell, and P.W. Shield. Related families with individual folders include the following families: Barraud, Beverley, Bowdoin, Guthrie, Merrick& Brewer, Peirsey, Pollard, Ruffin, Scott, and Skipwith.
Container List
- Barraud Family, 1966, n.d. (Box Box 1)
- Beverley Family, n.d. (Box Box 1)
- Bowdoin Family, 1951 (Box Box 1)
- Catalogue of Bremo Plantation Auction, 1926 Nov 18 (Box Box 1)
- Catalogue of an Exhibition of Paintings by Edward Troye, 1938 (Box Box 1)
- Cocke Family Coat of Arms by Robert Gall and Related Material, 1945 (Box Box 1)
- Cocke Family Notes & Research, 1929, 1949-1962, n.d. (Box Box 1)
- Cocke, Philip St. George, 1851, 1959 (Box Box 1)
- Cocke, Thomas, n.d. (Box Box 1)
- Cocke, William R.C.(1846-1884), including photograph, 1931, n.d. (Box Box 1)
- Correspondence re the Cocke Family, 1949-1971 (Box Box 1)
- Correspondence of William Ronald Cocke, 1950-1960 (Box Box 1)
- Correspondence of Alice L. de Coligny, 1952-1954 (Box Box 1)
- Correspondence of Elie Maury Fitzgerald, 1946-1950 (Box Box 1)
- Correspondence of R.P. Graham-Vivian, 1939-1951 (Box Box 1)
- Correspondence of T.P. Hughes, 1952 (Box Box 1)
- Correspondence of Forney & Joseph F. Johnston, ca. 1956-1973 (Box Box 1)
- Correspondence of Roberta McDonald Russell, 1950-1952 (Box Box 1)
- Correspondence of P.W. Shield, 1954-1960 (Box Box 1)
- "Eastnor Castle Ledbury Herefordshire" and the Malvern Hills (Box Box 1)
- Fluvanna County History, 1965 (Box Box 1)
- Genealogical Charts & Diagrams, n.d. (Box Box 1)
- Guthrie Family, n.d. (Box Box 1)
- "A List of the Wills and Administration of the Name of Cock(e), Cocks, Cox(e), Cook(e), in the Diocese of Hereford" (Box Box 1)
- Merrick& Brewer Families, 1950-1952 (Box Box 1)
- Peirsey Family, n.d. (Box Box 1)
- Photographs and Pictures including: " Bremo Recess, " " Lower Bremo, " Philip St. George Cocke, " Malvern Hills, " Cary Hartwell Cocke, " Bremo, " photostatic copy of Matthew Brady's photograph of Robert E. Lee, ca. 1940-1980 (Box Box 2)
- " Pickthorne", 1951, n.d. (Box Box 2)
- Pollard Family, 1927-1968 (Box Box 2)
- "Royal Descent of General John Hartwell Cocke", n.d. (Box Box 2)
- Ruffin Family, 1966-1967 (Box Box 2)
- Scott Family, 1920, 1951-1953 (Box Box 2)
- Skipwith Family, n.d. (Box Box 2)
- Society of the Cincinnati Application, including other historical societies, 1951-1959 (Box Box 2)
- Stottesdon and Chetton, England, ca. 1940's & n.d. (Box Box 2)
- Wills & Abstracts of Wills - England, Copies, ca. 1953-1959, n.d.; (2 folders) (Box Box 2)
- Wills & Abstracts of Wills - United States, Copies, n.d. (Box Box 2)
- Genealogical Chart of the Barraud Family, 1956 (Box Oversize Folder 1)
- Newspaper Article re " Bremo", 1931 (Box Oversize Folder 1)
- Photostatic Copies of Deeds and Records from Henrico County, Virginia, re the Cocke Family, ca. 1968 (Box Oversize Folder 1)
- Photographs of Philip St. George Cocke IV, Clara Merrick Guthrie Cocke, and unidentified, 1917, n.d. (Box Oversize Folder 1)
- Photostatic Copies of Wills, Deeds, & Other Records from Henrico County, and Surry County, Virginia, 1952, n.d. (Box Oversize Folder 2)
- Genealogical Charts re the Cocke Family, n.d. (Box Oversize Folder 2)